A Guide to the Virginia Historic Landmarks Commission, Architectural drawings, Virginia, 1904-1975 (bulk ca. 1970-1970)
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Virginia Historic Landmarks Commission, Architectural drawings, Virginia, 1904-1975 (bulk ca. 1970-1971)
Library of Virginia
41999
Consists of 258 sheets, mostly Mylar prints, some electrostatic prints of various sizes.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from the Special Collections Branch, Library of Virginia, Richmond, Virginia, 23 June 2005.
Biographical/Historical Information
Historic American Buildings Survey, microform (Fiche 27).The Historic American Buildings Survey (HABS) is a collection of documentary measured drawings, photographs, and written historical and architectural information for over 31,000 structures and sites in the United States and its territories. The effort began as a make-work program for unemployed draftsmen, architects, and photographers in 1933. In 1934 the National Park Service entered into an agreement with the Library of Congress and the American Institute of Architects (AIA) as cosponsors of the HABS program. Under the agreement the National Park Service continues to set qualitative standards and direct the preparation of records; the Library preserves the records, makes them available for study, and supplies reproductions to the public upon request; and the AIA provides professional counsel. The program continues today with the Historic American Buildings Survey(HABS)/Historic American Enginering Record (HAER) Summer Program. The complete collection of the HABS surveys is in the collection of the Library of Congress.
Scope and Content
This accession consists of 33 sets of architectural elevations, floor plans, and details of structures from across the Commonwealth of Virginia executed by the Virginia Historic Lanmarks Commission on behalf of the Historic American Buildings Survey. The drawings include structures in Accomack, Albemarle, Chesterfield, Dinwiddie, Essex, Greene, Northampton, Pittsylvania, Prince Edward, Rockbridge, Shenandoah, and Sussex Counties and Charlottesville, Hampton, Lexington, and Richmond Cities. Depicted are residences, mills, churches, and farm buildings.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by locality and then by structure name.
Contents List
- Accomack County, Mason House 1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Accomack County, Wessel's Root Cellar 1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Albemarle County, J. I. Maupin Store 1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Albemarle County, Morven Lawn Cottage 1971 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Albemarle County, Presbyterian Church (Scottsville) 1971 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Albemarle County, Stockton Creek Barn 1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Albemarle County, Warren Depot 1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Albemarle County, Wilhoit House 1971 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Augusta County, Rockfish Service Station 1971 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Charlottesville (City), Oaklawn 1971 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Chesterfield County, Richmond View 1975 (Box 4/G/8/10, Folder 11)
- Dinwiddie County, Mayfield 1971 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Essex County, Glebe House 1971 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Essex County, Ritchie House 1971 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Greene County, A. J. Long Mill 1971 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Hampton (City), Herbert House 1971 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Lexington (City), Alexander-Withrow House 1971 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Lexington (City), Reid-White 1971 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Lexington (City), Stono 1971 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Lexington (City), Thornhill 1971 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Northampton County, Pear Valley 1971 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Northampton County, Somers House 1971 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Northampton County, Westerhouse 1971 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Northampton County, Westover 1971 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Northampton County, Winona 1971 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Pittsylvania County, Cherrystone Farm 1971 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Prince Edward County, Briery Church 1971 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Richmond (City), G. G. Valentine House (1st and Franklin Sts.) 1971 (Box 4/G/8/10, Folder 28)
- Richmond (City), Iron Front Buildings (1017-1113 E. Main St.) 1971 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Richmond (City), Tucker Cottage 1904 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Rockbridge County, Winterview Log Cabin 1971 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Shenandoah County, Harmony Hall 1971 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Sussex County, Fortsville 1971 (Box 3, Folder 33)